<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" 
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:creativeCommons="http://backend.userland.com/creativeCommonsRssModule">
  <channel>
    <title>blog.timmschoof.com</title>
    <link>http://blog.timmschoof.com</link>
    <language>en</language>
	<image><url>http://blog.timmschoof.com/images/fav.png</url></image>
    <webMaster>hello@timmschoof.com (Timm Schoof)</webMaster>
    <pubDate>2011-06-27T21:41:21+02:00</pubDate>
    <creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    
    <item>
      <title>gmail finally got awesome on iOS</title>
      <link>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/25/gmail-finally-got-awesome-on-ios</link>
      <pubDate>Jun 25, 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/25/gmail-finally-got-awesome-on-ios</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since January, the native iOS app respects your settings in gmail regarding the 'Send Mail as' email address. That's exactly what I waited for. gmail is a great, if not &lt;strong&gt;the&lt;/strong&gt; tool for managing multiple email accounts. In these days of information, email overflow and 'just create an account' for me, that's crucial. But there are/were some drawbacks with gmail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I live in Germany, my account mail ends with '@googlemail.com' instead of '@gmail.com', due to some ridiculous legal restrictions (another company named gmail wanted to make some money). Back in 1800, when I created that google account, the term 'proxy' wasn't familiar to me, so now I have to live with the unnecessarily long domain. But that's not Google's fault.&lt;br/&gt;
I mentioned multiple accounts. gmail is the workhorse that does all your mail labeling, sorting, filtering, deleting, forwarding etc. But until January, you couldn't hide the fact that you're using gmail when you were using an iOS device. Mail on iOS would send every email from your gmail address, and not from the 'Send Mail as' you set in the gmail web app. This would've led to an inconsistency when you were mostly using some personal mail address with a nice domain for example, but mails from your iPhone would come from a different address.&lt;br/&gt;
My contacts would end up with the beautiful mail address I put on my card, maybe send me emails to it, and then, one day, get email from a different 'Timm Schoof' who's not in their contacts. 'Did you change your email address?' - '&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5oqgnKgwDsk&amp;amp;feature=youtube_gdta_player&quot;&gt;Yeah, no, yeah no, you know...&lt;/a&gt;'&lt;br/&gt;
I can't have that, I'm not a geek to have &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; conversation. It just wasn't a sophisticated or acceptable solution, considering all the effort I made configuring gmail for being my all-email-backend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned above, Google has solved that problem. Mail on iOS now sends emails from the email address you set in the 'normal' gmail web app. Unfortunately, Google &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/support/mobile/bin/answer.py?answer=138740&amp;amp;topic=14252&quot;&gt;buries&lt;/a&gt; the information how to get there deep I their support pages.&lt;br/&gt;
You need to go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.google.com/sync&quot;&gt;m.google.com/sync&lt;/a&gt; on your iDevice (that's where you can enable multiple calendars to sync with Google, too). Now, it gets messy. If you're accessing that site from outside the US or UK, as I was, it tells you: &lt;em&gt;Google Sync wird auf ihrem Gerät nicht unterstützt&lt;/em&gt;, German for: &lt;em&gt;Google Sync isn't available on your device&lt;/em&gt;. Bummer. The key lies within &lt;em&gt;Sprache ändern&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Change language&lt;/em&gt;. Switch to English and you're good to go. On the next page, you can access your Google Sync enabled devices and check &lt;em&gt;Enable 'Send Mail as' for this device&lt;/em&gt;, hit save and live in peace.&lt;br/&gt;
Of course, you have to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/support/mobile/bin/answer.py?answer=138740&amp;amp;topic=14252&quot;&gt;set up Google Sync with your iDevice&lt;/a&gt; i.e. Exchange Server, to use gmail like this. I strongly recommend this way of using it over IMAP or POP3 with some other host, and most likely even over the upcoming iCloud stuff. Cheers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven - "Add to Home Screen"</title>
      <link>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/25/seven-add-to-home-screen</link>
      <pubDate>Jun 25, 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/25/seven-add-to-home-screen</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;


&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; margin-top=&quot;10px&quot; &gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/apple-touch-icon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Apple Touch Icon&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
      <creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six - Font Magic</title>
      <link>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/24/six-font-magic</link>
      <pubDate>Jun 24, 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/24/six-font-magic</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had no idea! I was sabotaging my minimalistic approach towards this blog entirely by using the Ubuntu font all wrong.&lt;br/&gt;
I implemented it via @font-face and had &lt;strong&gt;nothing&lt;/strong&gt; but problems with getting f#ing Firefox to display it correctly. Yesterday, I spent several hours and finally got it fixed. The joy didn't las long: Since December of 2010, the Ubuntu font is available via the Google Font API, and I just discovered today that's a good thing. What did I do all the time instead of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts/family?family=Ubuntu&amp;amp;subset=latin#code&quot;&gt;using it&lt;/a&gt;? Let my visitors load some nice 1,5mb of font data. Yay.&lt;br/&gt;
Loading a font equals loading a font you might think: &lt;em&gt;Google has to load it too, stupid!&lt;/em&gt; -  Wrong. Well, yes but: I don't know whether github (where I'm hosted) slowed it all down, being free and and offering correspondent performance, but sure is: Now, with the Google Font API, this site loads amazingly fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Literally, one new line of code and 3 or 4 adjustments in my stylesheet was all it took. The latter solely due to my poor CSS skills and huge amount of &lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/buildanalyze/15&quot;&gt;technological debt&lt;/a&gt; I created. In case this is news to you - Everything necessary is to find here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://font.ubuntu.com/web/&quot;&gt;font.ubuntu.com/web&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game of Thrones</title>
      <link>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/23/Game-of-Thrones</link>
      <pubDate>Jun 23, 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/23/Game-of-Thrones</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is intended to be spoiler-free till the last paragraph&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Damn, what a great first season. Basically, medieval times aren't my favorite genre, but this world is more vivid than some of the worlds pictured in series with modern setting. I'm glad I began to watch '&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0944947/&quot;&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/a&gt;' when the 9th episode was already about to air, I don't know how psyched I would've got if I would've had to wait a whole week in between the single episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I thought I had recognized a change of scene and anticipated the next, but the current would continue and last almost twice as long as your average scene in films or other TV Series. To recognize how conditioned we are in these matters, I found quite shocking. However, the long lasting scenes and dialogues result in serious storytelling&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; and deeply drawn characters. They die like flies, but you get to know them very well beforehand. 'GoT' isn't called 'The Sopranos with swords' for nothing.&lt;br/&gt;
For not falling behind on whose sister sent a raven about whose murder to whose sister's husband, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://viewers-guide.hbo.com/game-of-thrones/#!/guide/houses/&quot;&gt;HBO's Viewer's Guide&lt;/a&gt;, it keeps you from googling and finding yourself on a wiki(pedia) page full of potential spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This series' dialogues are a joy to listen to, and they have a certain self-awareness to them. I also really like their humor. In one scene, King Robert Baratheon and his despised wife, Queen Cersei Lannister ask themselves what it was that held together the Kingdoms all these years. '&lt;em&gt;Our marriage?&lt;/em&gt;' he asks. Silence.&lt;br/&gt;
In other TV Series, this would've been a moment of weakness, in which the wannabe-sentimental  moment had been cheaply exploited for a kiss, so the masses could relax in their chairs and join the characters in their fake world, dreaming of theirs to be that simple. No, 'Game of Thrones' doesn't do that. After Robert asks the question, he and his wife burst out laughing and quickly settle on their hate to having held it all together. I almost applauded, but I couldn't, I clenched my fists in silent expression of gratitude to the writers and producers who didn't go down that road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also like the violence in this series. It's not omnipresent, but when it's there, it's raw, bloody, sometimes quite unexpected&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; and most of the time totally approved by everyone, even by the casualties-to-be. And you say our society is depraved about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about the rest? Some supernatural content and magic is beautifully justified with the world of 'Game of Thrones' being another universe than ours, adding other nice touches like seasons lasting for several years. Huge fan, out of pure longig for this fantasy world I already bought the first of the books&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; the series is based on. Maybe this one gets me to read novels again.&lt;br/&gt;
Can't wait for the second season. I just &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;attention, spoiling 9th episode&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; wonder if they casted Sean Bean solely as 'cart horse' for the first season. Otherwise I can't figure out why you'd slaughter the most popular actor of the cast, i.e. cast him for a (main) character who is decapitated in the first season, literally &lt;em&gt;by the book&lt;/em&gt;. I'm not arguing his death, it's okay, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/geekdad/2011/06/you-should-keep-watching-game-of-thrones/&quot;&gt;GeekDad is absolutely right&lt;/a&gt;: Letting the honest and honorable die makes the story, be it TV or novel, so good. Plus: In my opinion, Ned Stark was too whiny and naïve for King's Landing anyway. I mean, who has half his guard slaughtered more often?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do watch this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medieval people seem to scheme like masterminds, unimaginable for my modern age, lazy brain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well, the unseathing of the swords gives you an idea. I'd like an instrument like this nowadays. Imagine you walking down the street, someone gets in your way. Instead of walking by, doing nothing, you unsheathe your sword. Depending on how sophisticated you pull it off, you got yourself a slave, get  offered a match with his daughter or lose your head in duel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eBook, of course. Interesting: the English kindle edition is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.de/Game-Thrones-Song-Fire-ebook/dp/B000QCS8TW/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;m=A11MW6AJTK8WZ7&amp;amp;s=digital-text&amp;amp;qid=1308776721&amp;amp;sr=1-2&quot;&gt;5,67€&lt;/a&gt;, but in Germany there's a fixed price for books (hooray), so even the German eBook is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.de/Das-Lied-von-Feuer-ebook/dp/B004OVEY4O/ref=sr_1_5?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;m=A11MW6AJTK8WZ7&amp;amp;s=digital-text&amp;amp;qid=1308776721&amp;amp;sr=1-5&quot;&gt;9,99€&lt;/a&gt;. Almost as twice as much. The German publishers really must hate progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
      <creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AirPlay in Totem</title>
      <link>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/19/AirPlay-in-Totem</link>
      <pubDate>Jun 19, 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/19/AirPlay-in-Totem</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A plug-in for Totem (Ubuntu's standard movie player), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2011/01/airplay-video-playback-comes-to-totem/&quot;&gt;released in January&lt;/a&gt;, allows to stream video via Apple's AirPlay. I checked it out immediately, and it worked. With the release of Ubuntu 11.04, it stopped working. The plugin couldn't be activeated and Totem gave out the error message&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Unable to activate plugin AirPlay Support&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Then, I found the solution, a comment on the very same article I linked to above. Like &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/pgkehle&quot;&gt;Paul Kehle&lt;/a&gt; says, once you install 'avahi-discover', it works. Run&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install avahi-discover&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
in Terminal and you're fine. Thanks, Paul.&lt;br/&gt;
I just wanted to share this because I'd given up hope and just came across it by accident.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>work worth doing</title>
      <link>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/17/work-worth-doing</link>
      <pubDate>Jun 17, 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/17/work-worth-doing</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/16/The-work-you-should-be-doing/&quot;&gt;related matter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;
Patrick Rhone &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/patrickrhone/status/80270747922210816&quot;&gt;for one&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Far and away the best prize that life has to offer is the chance to work hard at work worth doing.” - &lt;em&gt;Theodore Roosevelt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patrick Rhone &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/patrickrhone/status/80271484723019776&quot;&gt;for two&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, of course, the question you must ask yourself is this: Are you doing work worth doing?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
      <creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The work you should be doing</title>
      <link>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/16/The-work-you-should-be-doing</link>
      <pubDate>Jun 16, 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/16/The-work-you-should-be-doing</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brooksreview.net/2011/04/qotd-hische/&quot;&gt;Jessica Hische&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The work you do while you procrastinate is probably the work you should be doing for the rest of your life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's a great sentence. It implies one of the principles I think is most important for one's professional life: Do something that's fun for you. I can't stand the idea of doing something for a living that doesn't appeal to me. This may sound harsh, but I'd rather shoot myself in the head than spend 30-40 years of my life doing something I don't like. It'd be pointless, too 'cause I really suck at doing things I don't like.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the quote above frightened me. It is great and true I think, but it frightened me. It frightened me because when I procrastinate, I check Twitter, watch TV Series or work on my blog.&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; And that has nothing to do with law in general or my studies in any other way. Well, don't I like studying law? Nah, that's not it, when I do intensified studying, it's fun. I really enjoy working on my very own solution for a case and write it up in some 30 pages. And I love to be right, so I just might as well make it my job. But to be honest, I constantly fail at getting a routine to do intense studying on a regular basis without any pressure, any deadline or exam.&lt;br/&gt;
So the quote above stood open in a page in the Safari on my iPad and I couldn't get it out of my head. I wanted to live by it, but what is it that kept me from doing so?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it got me thinking. There are hobbies that can be professions, like all this Web 2.0, Public Relations, Social Media, Designer stuff that takes place in lofts in the most expensive offices in town. It's real work, you don't need to tell me, but you don't have to read a book to do this kind of work. It's very likely anyone who now works as a graphic/web designer used to launch Photoshop (while procrastinating) and play with it.&lt;br/&gt;
And there are professions that can't be hobbies, and those are hard to come by while one procrastinates. It's very unlikely anyone without further knowledge of the law begins to ruminate on some civil law matter. In order to do so, you'd first need to acquire quite some knowledge. As one of my teachers used to put it: '&lt;em&gt;We have to chew some brown bread!&lt;/em&gt;', meaning there's some work to do that's not much fun, but obligatory. And I hate to admit it, but for me the crude ability to get over my weaker self and take on something that is not fun from the beginning is the most crucial skill in studying law.&lt;br/&gt;
It's like the postponing of 'do something that's fun for you' to reach a higher level of doing so is the ultimate challenge. This of course even applies to the decision of beginning a study or a job training after school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the above seems very obvious to me now that I read it, but it took me quite some time and thinking to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still looking at you, mark I got in French in 7th grade, still looking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The latter is more productive procrastinating, but it still isn't studying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
      <creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two more Apps in my 'workflow'</title>
      <link>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/13/two-more-apps-in-my-workflow</link>
      <pubDate>Jun 13, 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/13/two-more-apps-in-my-workflow</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I wrote about my &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/05/my-iOS-workflow&quot;&gt;iOS-centric workflow&lt;/a&gt;, or: funflow, I forgot to mention two apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the important one: &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/1password-pro/id319898689?mt=8&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1Password Pro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I keep all my passwords and account logins in it. It's one of the apps I launch most often, because it's all in one place. Once I got away from the foolish 'same password for every account' policy, I learned that one safe place to keep all the individually generated passwords is the only way to go. Of course, if my master password gets cracked my other passwords are worth nothing, that's the downside. Still, I think it's the only reasonable way to handle today's requirements of amounts of logins and passwords.&lt;br/&gt;
The Pro version is optimized both for iPhone and iPad, and looks and works marvelous, especially on the iPad. If you're lucky and use a Mac, it syncs to it. There also is a windows client that's supposed to sync via Dropbox, but I never figured out how. And by that, I mean it just doesn't work (yet). But you can back up your data manually in a single file. Attention: These files aren't necessarily interchangeable between iPad and iPhone because of different passcode-systems. Still a great app. There also is a non-pro version, but don't ask me what it can or can't do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you own an iDevice and are younger than 35 years, you probably already know the second app: &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/flipboard/id358801284?mt=8&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flipboard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It sucks in your Twitter, Faceboom and Instagram data and presents it in a beautiful way. So beautiful, I can't stand seeing the crappy status updates of my Facebook friends in it. But I love flipboarding the tweets I favorited once in a while.&lt;br/&gt;
Flipoard also signed deals with the Guardian, Wired and TechCrunch, probably to avoid getting sued over some copyright matter. But for your benefit: The Wired stories for example, are beautifully animated and integrated. For me, that's much more of a deal than the heavily advertised Wired Magazine App.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's it, for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter, Films and Bonds</title>
      <link>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/12/Twitter-Films-and-Bonds</link>
      <pubDate>Jun 12, 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/12/Twitter-Films-and-Bonds</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some time ago, on a Sunday evening, I had an idea. Everyone in Germany watches 'Tatort' on Sunday evenings, and so my Twitter timeline's full of it, too. The 'Tatort', somehow, isn't for me. Call me arrogant but I have to tell you that most of the time, I can't even stand original German TV anymore, not just the badly synchronized, US stuff. Maybe I just watch badly acted scenes whenever I peek in a German channel. However, I thought it would be great if everyone would watch something &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt; and tweet or blog about it. Like a book club, just for films.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the idea stayed an idea. Then, I started to listen to some &lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/&quot;&gt;5by5 podcasts&lt;/a&gt; and discovered that on The Talk Show, John Gruber and Dan Benjamin talk about every single one of the James Bond Films. They do kind of what I thought of! So, I liked the idea from the beginning.&lt;br/&gt;
I loved the Bond films a lot when I was younger, and I also like the reboot with Daniel Craig. And I like films and thinking, talking about them, especially considering the time they were made in and how they take effect today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having two dudes talking about films, listening to their opinions really works for me. Although I sometimes think Dan just agrees to whatever Gruber's opinion is, I use their discussion to think about the points they bring up and compare it to my opinion of the film. For instance, I honestly, really truly like the one with George Lazenby, '&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/LKkLF&quot;&gt;On Her Majesty's Secret Service&lt;/a&gt;', especially compared to the following 'Diamonds are forever' for which Connery was brought back and seemed completely uninspired and dull to me.&lt;br/&gt;
During the Roger Moore period, which sadly lasted more than a decade, you may start questioning yourself what the heck you are doing, wasting your time with some of the worst bond films&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;. But I have to say that as a kid, I loved the kind of humor Moore gave the character. This way, it's still fun to try to point the finger at what it is that makes the films so different than the Connery ones, and how much of it couldn't have been helped either way cause Moore's films were made in the 70s and 80s (and, how Gruber loves to point out, were directed by John Glen).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's it for now, I just wanted to address what I think is an interesting kind of film criticism and getting it out there. Maybe we/me/whoever can start a little something like this some time, realized through blogposts, another podcast, or just Twitter, we'll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which ones exactly are the worst is subject to heavy discussion, like you may have guessed. But I'm sure it's consent that quite a few, if not - let's say the worst two to three - are to find in Moore's era.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
      <creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes #1</title>
      <link>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/12/Quotes-1</link>
      <pubDate>Jun 12, 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/06/12/Quotes-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I've been wanting to write this post for a long time. I've been collecting quotes that made me laugh or want to clap my hands and shout &lt;strong&gt;'Right!'&lt;/strong&gt; when they were said. Today, I stumbled over &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siracusasaidso.com/&quot;&gt;SiracusaSaidSo.com&lt;/a&gt;, a neat website that collects some lines by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/siracusa&quot;&gt;John Siracusa&lt;/a&gt;. It reminded me of my plan. What follows are memorable quotes, mostly from different &lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/&quot;&gt;5by5 Podcasts&lt;/a&gt;, the network which's shows I currently mention in every post. I try to make the quotes as exact as possible but have to alter them a little in order to keep up the readability. Here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Magic of the Internet - &lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/hypercritical/1&quot;&gt;Hypercritical #1, 29:00&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
John Siracusa talks about TV, cable companies, TiVo, Netflix etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I'm paying all this money to all these different people and still end up downloading content because it's a better experience. It's HD, my cable company doesn't offer BBC America in HD, and I dont have to wait for it to appear on Netflix streaming. But through the magic of the internet an HD version of the thing appears after the day it airs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coffee - &lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/buildanalyze/9&quot;&gt;Build &amp;amp; Analyze #9, 14:00&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Marco Arment and Dan Benjamin talk about coffee, especially the chemex coffee brewer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marco:&lt;/strong&gt; It's the kind of hour-glass shaped coffee brewer with the big wooden handle in the midde. You've seen of those, right?&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Dan:&lt;/strong&gt; No.  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Marco:&lt;/strong&gt; What? Come on. Have you ever been anywhere cool ever? Oh yeah, that's why you live in Florida.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Geekism - &lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/buildanalyze/11&quot;&gt;Build &amp;amp; Analyze #11, 05:30&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Marco:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm a true geek. I like it when people are passionate and particular about things they really enjoy. So listening to other geeks talk about things in a geeky manner is still interesting to me, even if the topics are not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

  This reminds me of a sentence in the article &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.wilshipley.com/2011/04/success-and-farming-vs-mining.html&quot;&gt;Success, and farming vs mining&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The doctors and DNA-researchers and dancers and chocolate-makers and oceanographers and cosmologists and investors all have one thing in common: they are total nerds. They work on the thing they love literally all the time. You can't talk to them without talking about their passion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;  Here is an article in German I liked, too. It ruminates on a very related topic: Why someone without any enthusiasm is hard and unpleasant to talk to. UARRR.org - &lt;a href=&quot;http://uarrr.org/2010/08/27/begeisterungsfaehigkeit/&quot;&gt;Begeisterungsfähigkeit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being a designer - &lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/pipeline/43&quot;&gt;The Pipeline #43, 38:30&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/mike_ftw&quot;&gt;Mike Monteiro&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;And you can see on Twitter that there's a ton of bitching about: 'No one respects me as a designer. But I'm also not willing to put in the effort to get respected. I want to sit here at my desk in front of my iMac screen and my very expensive headphones on, listening to house music, cranking out beautifully layered Photoshop files that have nothing to do with my client's business goals.'&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ferrari - &lt;a href=&quot;http://minimalmac.com/enough/#ep18&quot;&gt;Enough #18, 06:00&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/patrickrhone&quot;&gt;Patrick Rhone&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didnt't buy a Ferrari to drive it on a 25 mph sideroad. I bought a Ferrari 'cause I want to drive it on the frikkin' Autobahn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
      <creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
