<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" 
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:creativeCommons="http://backend.userland.com/creativeCommonsRssModule">
  <channel>
    <title>blog.timmschoof.com</title>
    <link>http://blog.timmschoof.com</link>
    <language>en</language>
    <webMaster>hello@timmschoof.com (Timm Schoof)</webMaster>
    <pubDate>2011-05-11T12:15:54+02:00</pubDate>
    <creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two</title>
      <link>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/05/11/Two.html</link>
      <pubDate>May 11, 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/05/11/Two.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first thought about my new blog, the only options for me were: WordPress, Tumblr, maybe posterous. That was until &lt;a href=&quot;http://ivenwinkelmann.com/&quot;&gt;Iven&lt;/a&gt; told me about 'baked blogs'. What? - Yeah, that's what I thought, too.&lt;br/&gt;
Let me explain: In this analogy, the previously mentioned platforms 'fry' the blog in the second one requests them from the web server. They generate every page in the blog via PHP, I believe. Blogs served that way are 'fried blogs'.&lt;br/&gt;
Guess what: The server doesn't have to generate static files. So your blog has a fighting chance of staying online, even when it gets &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.23x.net/216/anatomy-of-a-fireballing.html&quot;&gt;fireballed&lt;/a&gt;.
Of course one can cache the fried files so they can be served more efficiently, and you lose the advantages of hosted platforms, i.e. blogging from on the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why I went baked&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in which universe does that bother me? Most certainly, my blog will never get fireballed or sweat a tear under heavy load of hundreds of thousands of visitors. I'm not that into web server stuff that I could't bear with what some people may call an unsophisticated solution. So?&lt;br/&gt;
What made me consider a baked blog more seriously was that with wordpress, I always had the feeling to utilize something I didn't understand entirely. Using wordpress is simple, but to customize it is much harder. Therefore it's likely you just use it in a very standard way. That's ok for most people, I would suggest that for nearly everyone who's inclined to dive into the world of blogging. Which I strongly suggest, too.&lt;br/&gt;
I, for my part, &lt;em&gt;knew&lt;/em&gt; that I would be able to teach myself (or: remind) enough HTML and CSS to code something suitable for a static file generator (that's how you call the things that bake your blog). I knew that the second I heard of baked blogs, even thought I didn't realize it immediately.&lt;br/&gt;
Now, my blog only contains code I wrote myself or ripped off somebody else's git repository, knowing what it does and where to put it. To me, that's &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; appealing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Jekyll&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did I chose &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;? At first I didn't want to. After Iven &lt;a href=&quot;http://ivenwinkelmann.com/journal/my-take-on-baked-blogs/&quot;&gt;told me about baked blogs&lt;/a&gt;, I listened to an episode of Build &amp;amp; Analyze (&lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/buildanalyze/18&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;, but the following ones also fit the topic) in which Marco Arment (the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.instapaper.com/iphone&quot;&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt; guy) talked about his plans to release his self-written static site generator, 'Second Crack' on github. I also am a coffee nut, so its name (a specific point of time in the roasting process of coffee) made me want to use it. In the end, the idea that I was using this as an excuse to put the whole project off became a certainty, so I chose Jekyll, and here I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be acurate: If you're interested in this topic, you propably want to read Brent Simmons' piece on it: &lt;a href=&quot;http://inessential.com/2011/03/16/a_plea_for_baked_weblogs&quot;&gt;A plea for baked weblogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One</title>
      <link>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/05/10/one.html</link>
      <pubDate>May 10, 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.timmschoof.com/2011/05/10/one.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, it's here. My new blog. Self-hosted, home-baked, 100% hand-crafted. A bunch of HTML files, one CSS file, a header, a favicon, a jekyll-installation, one 'jekyll --server' command, an upload to my FTP server (my deployment method so far), that's it.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;OMG&lt;/strong&gt;, I can't believe how long I put this off, this progress that took me about two days of 'coding', if my method of c&amp;amp;p combined with trial&amp;amp;error qualifies as such. It's funny: You might think I'm fishing for compliments here, but that's just the case if you're worse than me when it comes to HTML and such. If you're not, then you're probably laughing at my style.css' structure right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway: I'm proud like Tom Hanks in 'Cast Away', when he finally managed to start a fire. Me can haz blog! But most important: I no longer can keep myself from writing by thinking that in order to do so, I would first need to build a new blog cause the last project's dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;future&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will talk about little aspects, decisions and stuff that yet has to be done regarding this blog. As you may know, in the first few days of such a project nothing is just 'done', everything gets a pretty short half-life. Therefore I will comment the further construction of this site as it happens.&lt;br/&gt;
So I'll handle it just like Iven announced on &lt;a href=&quot;http://ivenwinkelmann.com/journal&quot;&gt;his blog&lt;/a&gt;, a quite similar project. Similar does not quite describe it, to tell the truth: I have to thank Iven, without him doing a lot of research and waving in front of my nose with sophisticated solutions, I wouldn't have developed the urge to build a non-wordpress-hosted blog from scratch.&lt;br/&gt;
Thanks, buddy. (Is 'mindfork' a word? This github stuff messes with my head)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
